Matthew Richardson Full Stack Developer

SUMMARY:

Candidate is a web developer with 8 years professional experience in web development and a degree in Information Systems. He is currently at Nottingham as a full stack web developer. He led the development of the client portal and accounting reports using Vue JS, JavaScript, PHP, and SQL.

HIGHLIGHTS:

- 8 years of JavaScript and PHP experience.
- Hands on development with Vue, React, Node.js and Laravel.
- Experience working with a team and building web apps from inception to deployment.

LINKEDIN PROFILE:

SKILLS:

<u>Front-end:</u> Vue.js, React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, responsive mobile design, UI/UX Design, jQuery, Bootstrap.

Back-end: PHP, JavaScript, ASP.NET, Python, Laravel.

<u>Data Storage & Transfer:</u> SQL, MySQL, Oracle, Oracle Database 21c, Microsoft SQL Server Studio, PhpMyAdmin, dBeaver.

<u>Tools/Practices:</u> Git, GitHub, VS Code, Linux, Node.js, NPM, CI/CD, Vite, Composer, Object Oriented Programming, MVC, Netlify, UI design, UX design, Agile.

EXPERIENCE:

Full Stack Web DeveloperRocky Mount, NCNottingham2014 - Present

- Transformed the investment process by designing and developing a cutting-edge investor transaction system using a combination of JavaScript on the front end and a robust PHP Model-View-Controller (MVC) API on the backend, resulting in a seamless and efficient experience for all users.
- Lead end-to-end development, testing, and deployment of critical client portal features, including advanced user authentication, password management, an intuitive email notification system, two-factor authentication, and session management, using PHP libraries and industry best practices.
- Improved accuracy and efficiency of data by creating web tools and automating processes to import and export financial data into the Oracle Database.
- Heightened user satisfaction and improved system security or apps by collaborating with the team and having strong communication with clients.
- Raised awareness of cyber-attacks by developing a cyber security training web app with JavaScript, jQuery animations, Responsive Bootstrap design and dynamic PHP features.
- Reinforced security of data by implementing encryption in MySQL databases and PHP OpenSSL.
- Introduced modern responsive web designs, allowing clients to effectively view pages on any device, using HTML, CSS, and media queries.
- Eliminated Legal documentation obstacles by creating a questionnaire system that allowed Legal to create, send, schedule, and review questionnaires via JavaScript, React.js, and LAMP stack.
- Solved Software development documentation insufficiencies by creating a project management app to record support requests and project life cycles, while using JavaScript and PHP for handling HTTP requests.

Matthew Richardson Full Stack Developer

• Secured sensitive documents by collaborating with HR and managing the production of a secure online file manager using PHP directory features. This allowed new and existing employees to create an account and upload files instead of sending via email.

Freelance Web DesignUnited StatesSelf-employed2018 - Present

- Created an online Photography Portfolio using React, JSX and Node.js Styled components using React-Bootstrap library. Used git for version control. Deployed the app using Netlify. Implement SEO best practices.
- Revolutionized the online presence of an auto-repair shop by spearheading the design and
 development of a sleek and responsive website. Employing state-of-the-art technologies such as
 GitHub Pages for hosting, Bootstrap, CSS media queries, and Flexbox for mobile web design, in
 addition to utilizing FormSpree for contact forms, resulting in an engaging and user-friendly
 experience for clients.
- Experience configuring Shopify online stores.

EDUCATION:

North Carolina Wesleyan College

Rocky Mount, NC

B.S., Information Systems

2010 - 2014

- Senior project resulted in creation of a website for listing rental properties using HTML, CSS, SQL, and PHP.
- Learned best practices of programming while learning Java, C++, JavaScript, PHP, and Visual
- Drummer for the Jazz Band and Pep Band